So now what I would like to do is I would like to add
现在 我想在此 UI 上添加一个重置按钮
a reset button to this UI so that when I click it,
这样的话 当我点击该按钮时
it resets this information for the specific day.
它会重置特定日期的这些信息
So what we will do,
我们先在这里
is let's import a few methods here.
导入一些方法
The first one is add entry and if you'll remember,
首先导入 addEntry
it is an action creator that we created a long time ago,
它是我们在很早之前创建的一个 action creator
and then the second one is going to come from our API file.
接着 从 api 文件中导入 removeEntry
It's called remove entry and it's going to remove this specific entry from our database.
它将从数据库中删除特定的条目
Now what we need to do is let's go ahead and create a map dispatch to props function,
现在创建一个 mapDispatchToProps 函数
which is going to take and dispatch and
传入 dispatch
then we will also get navigation coming from the props.
然后传入来自属性的 navigation
First thing, as we've done a few times,
首先 和之前一样
let's go ahead and get the entry ID that we're passing
获取传递的 entryId
along and then what we want to do is we want to return two different methods.
然后返回两种不同的方法
One, which is going to go ahead and remove the item for the specific day from our store,
一个是从 store 中删除特地日期的项目
and the other one is just going to allow us to navigate back to the home view.
另一个方法使我们能够转到主屏幕视图
What we can do is remove.
输入 remove
What this is going to do is it's going to call dispatch and then we are going to invoke
它将调用 dispatch
our add entry action creator and then now
然后调用 addEntry action creator
what we are going to do is we will say entry ID.
现在输入 [entryId]
At this specific entry ID,
在此 entryId 下
what we want to do is we want to say,
我们要做的是...
we basically want to reset this.
我们要重置信息
The problem here is, if you remember and this is where the app kind of gets tricky,
问题是 如果你还记得的话…现在应用有点复杂了
is if the day that we're setting is the current day instead of resetting it to null,
如果我们要重置的日期是当天 则不能重置为 null
we want to reset it to this right here.
而是重置为这些信息
What we can say is up here in entry detail,
转到 EntryDetail
let's go ahead and import two different things.
导入两项内容
The first one is going to be time two strings so we get the ID of
第一个是 timeToStrings 以便获得当前日期的 ID
the current day and then the second one is going to be get daily reminder value,
第二个是 getDailyReminderValue
which is going to give us that object for the day.
以便获得该日期的对象
Now what we can do is,
现在 转到这里
instead of here wher you can say we want the entry for this specific day,
我们希望获得该特地日期的条目
when we remove it,
当我们删除它时
to be either if time two string equals the entry ID.
要么设为 timeToString === entryId
If we're on today,
如果是今天
then go ahead and just make it whatever gets returned from get daily reminder value,
则设为 getDailyReminderValue 返回的内容
which is that way that says, "Hey,
也就是提示
don't forget to lock your data," or we set it equal to null.
“嘿 别忘了记录数据” 或设为 null
Now, the second thing that we want to add to this object is
我们要添加到该对象的第二个内容是 goBack
say go back and all this is going to do is it's going to call navigation dot go back.
调用 navigation goBack()
All right. Now we have access to remove and go back
现在我们可以在组件中访问 remove 和 goBack 了
inside of our component so what we can do here,
转到我们的组件中
is we can have a reset method.
在这里设置一个 reset 方法
What this is going to do,
它的作用是
so whenever we click reset what we want to do is let's go ahead and first grab remove,
每当我们点击 reset 首先获取 remove
go back in the entry ID,
goBack 和 entryId
coming in from the stop props,
来自于 this.props
and entry ID is coming in from right here in MapStateToProps.
entryId 来自于 MapStateToProps 中的这个 entryId
Then what we want to do is we call remove.
然后调用 remove()
We call it go back,
调用 goBack()
and then we call remove entry,
然后调用 removeEntry()
which is coming in from right here in our API file passing it the entry ID.
来自于 api 文件中的这里 传入 entryId
This looks pretty good so far.
到目前为止 看起来不错
Now, let's just set up a UI to invoke reset.
现在设置一个 UI 来调用 reset
So what I'm going to do is import text button,
导入 TextButton
which is coming from the text button component and then now here,
来自于 TextButton 组件
instead of this long thing,
然后将这段长长的代码改为
what we can say is text button and then here,
TextButton
we can say onPress equals the this resets.
在这里输入 onPress=
We will give it a style, say margin 20.
margin 设为 20
The text we'll say is reset.
文本为“RESET”
Now, this looks pretty good.
看起来不错
Let's see if we get any errors we do so we need to resolve action.
看看是否有任何错误 的确有。需要解决 action 问题
I believe that should be actions.
应该是 actions
Alright. So, so far so good let's see how the UI looks, pretty good.
到目前为止一切正常 看看 UI 看起来怎样 很不错
One thing we're going to run into,
我们将遇到的一个情况是
if we hit reset as it currently is,
如果点击 reset
is what's going to happen is this component is going to re-render but then,
现在会出现的情况是 这个组件将重新渲染
it's going to break because what it's going to try to
然后将会出现故障
do is get state at the specific entry ID,
因为它会尝试获取特定 entryId 的状态
which if it's not on the current day,
如果不是当前日期
is going to be null,
则将为 null
and then we pass all of those metrics into MetricCard, which then breaks.
然后将所有 metrics 传入 MetricCard 接着就会出现故障
There's a few ways we can solve this.
这个问题可以有几种解决方法
What I think is the most elegant way is what we want to do is we can say,
我认为最合适的方法是
should the component update and we can say if
输入 shouldComponentUpdate
nextProps.metrics does not equal null and nextProps.metrics.today is falsie,
如果 nextProps.metrics 不为 null 并且 nextProps.metrics.today 为假
then the component should update.
那么该组件应该更新
But if it's not,
但是如果不是这种情况
then we don't want the component to update.
则不更新组件
Again, what's happening here is when I click reset,
当我点击 reset
the component is naturally going to re-render even though we're going back
组件将自然地重新渲染 虽然我们要回到主屏幕
to home because the entry detail is still in the route stack,
因为 EntryDetail 依然在路径堆栈中
but what we're doing,
而 shouldComponentUpdate 的作用是
we should about an update is we're saying don't re-render unless
不要重新渲染组件
nextProps.metrics does not equal null.
除非 nextProps.metrics 不等于 null
So the day has current information in it and nextProps.metrics.today is falsie.
表示日期具有当前信息 并且 nextProps.metrics.today 为假
Without this line, again,
没有这行代码的话
what would happen is MetricCard would render passing in metrics,
则 MetricCard 将渲染 并传入 metrics
which would just be undefined and then everything would just break.
它将是 undefined 一切会出现故障
Let's go ahead and see if this is working properly.
看看应用能否正常运行
We'll go to the 29th. Let's reset it.
转到 29 日 点击重置
Remove is not a function.
系统提示 remove 不是一个函数
Sure it is, it's the props.
肯定是啊 this.props
We didn't even pass and map to special props as
啊哈 我们没有传入第二个参数 mapDispatchToProps
the second argument so we pass that in and now,
传入该参数
I'm at least roughly confident this will work so we hit reset.
现在 我觉得有信心一切正常 点击 RESET
Now, notice August 29th instead of saying the information for that day,
8 月 29 日不再显示当天的信息
it says you didn't log any data on this day.
而是提示“You didn't log any data on this day.”